

Adrián Silva Fernández iOS Developer

Twitter

LinkedIn

GitHub

Email

Phone

About me

I'm an iOS developer currently living in Barcelona. My passions, when it comes to software development, are: functional programming, software architecture and product design. I've been developing iOS apps professionally for two years, mostly using reactive frameworks and programmatic UI interfaces.

Experience

FREENOW – iOS Developer

August 2019 - Current

- Driver app
- Scrum framework
- RxSwift and Redux style architecture
- TDD approach when writing code
- Xcode UITests
- Responsive interfaces and animations with Autolayout and Core Animation
- Development of new features from design to implementation
- Setup A/B tests to validate the success of new features
- Generation of Xcode projects with Tuist

Quobis – iOS Developer

April 2018 - July 2019

- Responsive interfaces with Autolayout
- Development of apps for clients using internal SDKs and WebRTC
- RxSwift and MVVM-C architecture
- Started learning about testing methodologies

Education

The Keepcoding – Mobile Engineering Bootcamp

June 2018 - June 2019

- Modern Mobile Architectures & Paradigms: MVC, MVVM, MVP, VIPER...
- Advanced Git: Git flow
- Introduction to backend development with Node.js & Express.js
- Mobile DevOps: AWS, Linux, Docker, Fastlane, Jenkins...
- iOS Fundamentals: Intro to functional Swift, Swift fundamentals, TDD, BDD, DDD...
- Advanced iOS: Autolayout, MapKit, RxSwift, WatchOS, Realm, CoreData, ARKit, CoreML...
- Mobile design with Sketch
- Android fundamentals: Room, Coroutines, Networking...

- Advanced Android
- React for mobile developers
- Multiplatform development with React Native
- Firebase: Cloud Storage, Cloud functions, Firestore, Analytics, Crashlytics...
- Intro to GraphQL
- Agile project management (using Scrum)

CPR Daniel Castelao

June 2018 - June 2019

Higher Technician in Software Development

Courses

KARUMI - Testing Training

April 2019

- TDD, BDD & DDD applied to iOS development
- Snapshot testing
- Xcode UITests
- Refactoring code to make it testable

Skills

